<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 VMSolidus
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 sleepyyapril
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Jakumba

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
  Welcome to the Den!

  With how our rules, space law, and SOP are written, it'd be too large a task to update this page with them every time, so be sure to give them a read at:
  [bold][color=pink]wiki.denstation.net[/color][/bold]

  We are a roleplay-focused server that allows ERP, which means that antags are to move a story forward rather than focus on ending the round. We are also focused on the comfort of all our players, and strongly encourage sending an ahelp, using the "I Am Uncomfortable" button found in your consent menu, or creating a ticket in the Discord server. If you see something you don't enjoy, such as overhearing ERP when you didn't want to, you're encouraged to speak up; the worst we can say is thank you. All the admins are here to help and listen, we want you to feel safe! We can't take care of any problems if you don't tell us!

  You can get in contact with us (via ahelp) for any manner of reason. Common ones we see include:

  [bullet/][color=#81BABA][bold]Requesting an early respawn[/bold][/color] to bypass the fifteen minute wait, because certain traits are missing, loadout items are missing, height and/or width is wrong, the wrong job was selected, so on.

  [bullet/][color=#81BABA][bold]Requesting a "coords" announcement[/bold][/color], where some kind of accident/situation happened that leaves a person round removed (ex: accidentally walking off station, getting hit by debris, dying alone in Lavaland)-- a message gets sent to the station with coordinates, so a rescue team can be sent.

  [bullet/][color=#81BABA][bold]Requesting specific items, tools, or resources[/bold][/color] to amplify a player's round, whether it be helping with character roleplay, building something unique on station, or the privacy of ERP (note: for the comfort and consent of the admin team, please keep details of your ERP to a minimum when requesting items for it; simply state it's "for a scene")

  If you're in round (playing or observing), there should be a gear icon somewhere along the top-- that's the consent menu, where you can write out your preferences on what you do and do not like. You can find character-specific options of this and others in your character's description area; please do make sure to say what you feel is necessary for your character.
  Examples of what you can write include relationship RP (open to dating, commitment), avoidance of certain items (cigarettes, alcohol, needles), bedroom preferences (likes, dislikes), antag interaction (open invitations, prevalent character information), and more.
  [color=#81BABA][bold]You can also access the consent menu in the lobby![/bold][/color] Hit the tilda key (~) and type in "consentprefs" to pull it up!

  Patreon: [bold][color=pink]denstation.net/patreon[/color][/bold]

  All other links including our rules and SOP: [bold][color=pink]https://denstation.net[/color][/bold]
</Document>
