<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 VMSolidus
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 sleepyyapril
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Jakumba
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 portfiend

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
  Welcome to the Den!

  With how our rules, space law, and SOP are written, it'd be too large a task to update this page with them every time, so be sure to give them a read at:
  [bold][color=pink]wiki.denstation.net[/color][/bold]

  —————

  [color=green]Eternity[/color] is The Den's Greenshift-only server. There will be no gamerules (automated events), threats, or antagonists, unless an admin chooses to add them (which would be rare). The intention of Eternity is to be a lower-stakes server with higher emphasis on in-character conversation and light gameplay.

  Some mechanical differences between Eternity and Salvation include:

  [bullet] Rounds last [color=orange]five hours[/color], compared to Salvation rounds lasting three to five hours.

  [bullet] Eternity has a maximum of 40 players, instead of 80.

  [bullet] Many departments are much smaller, simpler, or outright missing, including [color=#DE3A3A]Security[/color], [color=#D381C9]Epistemics[/color], [color=#EFB341]Engineering[/color], and [color=#334E6D]Command[/color]. For the most part, the main "department" gameplay will be [color=#9FED58]Service[/color].

  [bullet] [color=#A46106]Logistics[/color] is self-serve; the station is allocated a budget at the beginning of the round, and players may order items at their leisure. There is no ATS; items are delivered via telepad. Special items can be requisitioned via fax to [color=Green]CentComm[/color]. Many "dangerous" Logistics orders have been disabled.

  [bullet] [color=#52B4E9]Medical[/color] is also reduced in size and largely self-serve, save for one or two staff; the vendors are meant to be free access to treat minor injuries and damage. There should be very little actual death in Eternity, especially from interpersonal conflict.

  [bullet] [color=orange]Eternity has its own map rotation[/color] to accommodate these changes; much safer and more leisurely than the work stations found on Salvation.

  [bullet] There is [color=orange][bold]no[/bold] respawn timer[/color] on Eternity, allowing you to jump in and out of the round instantly without admin intervention.

  If you choose to take on a working/departmental role in-round, we expect you to be working in that role, or be available if called; if you would like to set aside your duties for roleplay, please enter cryosleep and rejoin as a passenger first.

  We ask you to help keep the atmosphere of Eternity low in chaos and intensity, and we hope you enjoy the server. As always, please feel free to Ahelp for concerns, requests, and reports.
</Document>
