
<Document>
# Sequence Cooking

Tired of the same boring burgers and tacos? Looking to put the "art" back into "culinary arts"? Perhaps you're looking to open your own restaurant chain at the heart of a Nanotrasen station... well, we can't approve your business license, but we do have just the advanced Taco Tech for you!

First, pick the ingredient that will serve as the basis of your meal:

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodBreadBun" Caption="burger"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodKebabSkewer" Caption="kebab"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodTacoShell" Caption="taco"/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodBreadBun" Caption="bun"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="KitchenKnife" Caption="slice"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodBreadBunBottom" Caption="bottom bun"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodBreadBunTop" Caption="top bun"/>
</Box>

Then, you can simply stack ingredients directly on your base with your hands. Note that [italic]not all ingredients[/italic] may be usable in a burger or taco... but don't be afraid to experiment! You might be surprised by what you can add to a burger or taco.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodMeatCutletCooked" Caption=""/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodCheeseSlice" Caption=""/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodTomato" Caption=""/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodChiliPepper" Caption=""/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodCabbage" Caption=""/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OrganHumanBrain" Caption=""/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodCorn" Caption=""/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodOrange" Caption=""/>
</Box>

<Box HorizontalAlignment="Center" VerticalAlignment="Stretch">
  [italic]Don't forget to finish your burger with a top bun![/italic]
</Box>

There are some interesting quirks of this system. For example, generally, you can only use [color=orange]cooked[/color] meat, not raw.

Another one is that the chemical composition of your meal is based on the ingredients used to fill it. For example, if you have a steak with barbecue sauce on it, and add that to a burger, then the burger will have barbecue sauce on it as well.

This may have some [color=orange]interesting[/color] applications - I'm sure you can think of a few!

## Metamorphic Recipes

In some cases, you can create pre-existing food items through a cooking sequence. This mainly applies to [bold]burgers[/bold] - using cutlets in place of meat from the original recipe, certain recipes can be recreated.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodBreadBunBottom" Caption="bun"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodMeatCutletCooked" Caption="cutlet"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodCheeseSlice" Caption="cheese"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodBreadBunTop" Caption="bun"/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodBurgerCheese"/>
</Box>

You may notice that by cutting a steak into three cutlets, this method of making cheeseburgers can [color=orange]save resources[/color] compared to the original, microwave-based cheeseburger recipe. Again, don't be afraid to experiment.

In addition, metamorphic recipes are a bit more flexible compared to the original microwave recipe. You could use a different type of meat cutlet, or you could add two cutlets or cheese wedges instead of one - it would still work. For metamorphic recipes that use chemical reagents, you might even be able to get away with saving a few units.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodBreadBunBottom" Caption="bun"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodMeatBearCutletCooked" Caption="bear"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodMeatDuckCutletCooked" Caption="duck"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodCheeseSlice" Caption="cheese"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodBreadBunTop" Caption="bun"/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodBreadBunBottom" Caption="bun"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodMeatChickenCutletCooked" Caption="chicken"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ReagentContainerMayo" Caption="mayonnaise"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodBreadBunTop" Caption="bun"/>
</Box>

</Document>
