<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 VMSolidus <evilexecutive@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 portfiend <109661617+portfiend@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 sleepyyapril <123355664+sleepyyapril@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later AND MIT
-->

<Document>
  # Harpy (Homo-Aves sapiens)

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobHarpyDummy" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  An avian humanoid species that can mimic almost any sound, featuring colorful feathered wings and tails.

  They natively know the Valyrian Standard language.

  ## Positive Traits
  - [color=#1e90ff]Mimicry[/color]:
  Harpies can mimic almost any sound in the game using emotes, barring only a few exceptions. This includes the voice emotes of every other species.
  The Harpy sound library contains nearly 700 possible sounds. This trait is unique only to Harpies.

  - [color=#1e90ff]Runner[/color]:
  Thanks to their incredibly light build, a Harpy's base running speed is 10% faster than that of a standard Human.

  - [color=#1e90ff]Singer(Advanced)[/color]:
  Harpies have a significantly more advanced variant of the [color=#1e90ff]Singer[/color] trait. This trait gives a Harpy access to an innate Midi Player, as well as a menu for swapping instruments.
  Right click on yourself to open the Swappable Instrument menu, and select from a list of available instruments to mimic. Any of the following conditions both stop and prevent a Harpy from singing:

    ◦ Being Mute

    ◦ Being Zombified

    ◦ Being Dead or Crit

    ◦ Taking more than 5 damage in a single instance

    ◦ Being shoved to the ground

  - [color=#1e90ff]Zero Gravity Flight[/color]:
  Harpies have significantly enhanced acceleration in zero gravity. This trait is shared with Nians.

  - [color=#1e90ff](Limited) True Flight[/color]:
  Harpies have an activatable ability to attempt to fly. In order to fly, a Harpy must have both of their wings unencumbered, either by carrying something in hand, or by being restrained.
  When activated, Flight significantly increases the maximum speed and acceleration of a Harpy, while allowing them to fly over obstacles.
  Using flight costs a significant amount of stamina.

  - [color=#1e90ff]Talons[/color]:
  Functions as per the [color=#1e90ff]Talons[/color] trait. A Harpy's unarmed attacks deal 5 points of Piercing damage.

  ## Negative Traits
  - [color=#ffa500]Asthmatic[/color]:
  Using their powerful Avian Lungs, a Harpy breathes twice as deeply, and twice as often as a standard Human. This results in two key conditions. The first is that all oxygen tanks last half as long for a Harpy.
  The second condition, is that Harpies are uniquely vulnerable to poisonous fumes. When exposed to even a small amount of Carbon Dioxide and or Ammonia, a Harpy will shortly thereafter being to choke.
  Choking can be ended either by moving away from the sources of poisonous fumes(such as rotting bodies, open gas tanks, or several people in an enclosed space with no scrubbers).
  A choking Harpy can also stop themselves from choking by breathing from a tank of Pure Oxygen for at least 6 seconds.

  - [color=#ffa500]Extreme Low Density[/color]:
  The average weight of a Harpy is only 24kg, and can be as low as 10kg, with a maximum of 31kg. Because of this, Harpies suffer from any form of Mass Contests.
  This results in weaknesses such as- but are not limited to:
    - Experiencing more recoil with firearms
    - Being easier to shove down
    - Being easy to pick up by other people
    - Being easy to throw
    - Having a harder time pushing or dragging heavy objects
    - Having weaker melee damage with certain weapons
    - Being thrown extremely easily by Space Wind

  - [color=#ffa500]Hollow Bones[/color]:
  Harpies take 15% greater damage from any source of Brute damage.

  - [color=#ffa500]Ultraviolet Vision[/color]:
  Harpies have a unique kind of eye lens that lets them see in Ultraviolet-Blue-Green, but that they cannot see the color Red. This functions as per the Ultraviolet Vision trait.
  "Ultravision" can also be "Bought off" in character creation by taking the [color=#1e90ff]Trichromat Modification[/color] trait.

  ## Unique Traitor Items

  - [color=#1e90ff]Bionic Syrinx[/color]:
  Traitor Harpies can optionally purchase a Bionic Syrinx. This takes the form of an Implant which- when implanted in a Harpy, acts as an internal Voice Changer.
  The Bionic Syrinx will only work on Harpies.

</Document>
