<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Memeji <greyalphawolf7@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Timemaster99 <57200767+Timemaster99@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 portfiend <109661617+portfiend@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 sleepyyapril <123355664+sleepyyapril@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later AND MIT
-->

<Document>
  # I.P.C.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobIPCDummy" Caption=""/>

  [color=#808080]IPCs are [color=#b3b3b3]"adults"[/color] until age 150, [color=#b3b3b3]older[/color] until age 250, and [color=#b3b3b3]ancient[/color] beyond that point.[/color]

  An IPC (short for Integrated Positronic Chassis) is a type of sentient robot and is considered an [color=yellow]independent individual[/color], meaning [color=red]they are not guided by any laws of robotics[/color]. IPCs cannot be hacked by Emags because they do not have to follow any predefined directives in their system. [color=red]IPCs are silicon-based beings, so doctors do not have the skills to repair them.[/color] Instead, they are to be taken to [color=purple]Epistemics[/color] to be repaired by the Roboticist.

  Being robots, they natively know how to speak RobotTalk.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PositronicBrain" Caption="Positronic Brain"/>
  </Box>
  Like borgs, IPCs have a positronic brain as their processing source. However, unlike them, IPCs can't be assembled due to the complexity of their assembly to make them sentient.

  ## Recharging an IPC
   <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="APCBasic" Caption="APC Terminal"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgCharger" Caption="Borg Charger"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PowerCellMedium" Caption="Power Cell"/>
  </Box>
  IPCs can be recharged in three different ways:

  APC Terminal: IPCs can use APC terminals to recharge. Press [color=yellow]Alt + left click[/color] on a terminal as many times as needed to fully recharge.

  Borg Rechargers: IPCs can use borg rechargers to recharge. Always prioritize the ones outside of the Sci area to avoid headaches.

  Power Cell: IPCs have an internal power cell that serves as their battery. They can simply swap it out by opening the hatch and manually replacing it.

  ## Integrated Radio
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EncryptionKeyScience" Caption="Encryption key"/>
  </Box>

  IPCs do [bold]not[/bold] use external radios because they already have one built in. They only need to get an encryption key from a radio. By clicking on an IPC with a [color=yellow]wire cutter[/color], you can remove their keys.
  You can find new keys around the station or remove one from a sector radio using a [color=yellow]screwdriver[/color].

  ## Repairing
  <Box HorizontalAlignment="Stretch">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WelderIndustrialAdvanced" Caption="Welder"/>
    Welders can be used to repair [color=yellow]Brute[/color] damage.
  </Box>
  <Box HorizontalAlignment="Stretch">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CableApcStack" Caption="Cables (any type)"/>
    Cables can be used to repair [color=yellow]Burns[/color].
  </Box>
  <Box HorizontalAlignment="Stretch">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SheetGlass" Caption="Glass Sheets (any type)"/>
    Glass Sheets can be used to repair [color=yellow]Blindness[/color].
  </Box>
  <Box HorizontalAlignment="Stretch">
    In the event an IPC dies, after being fully repaired, it should be restarted using the [color=yellow]"Restart"[/color] button (located by right-clicking).

    [color=red]NEVER ELECTROCUTE AN IPC with a defibrillator or in any other way while it is dead, as this will cause the battery to discharge its stored energy outward![/color]
  </Box>

</Document>
