<Document>
  # Thaven

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobThaven" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  [color=#808080]Thaven are [color=#b3b3b3]young adults[/color] until age 50, [color=#b3b3b3]adults[/color] until age 100, [color=#b3b3b3]middle-aged[/color] until age 150, [color=#b3b3b3]older[/color] until age 200, and [color=#b3b3b3]elderly[/color] beyond that point.[/color]

## Moods
  Thaven have a unique brain structure that's similar to a positronic brain, and thus have "moods" which affect them similarly to a borg's laws.

  [color=#1e90ff]You must take the Thaven Moods mental trait to access this feature![/color] All thaven naturally have moods, so if your character does not have this trait, it should be said that they have mood-regulating implants, an ion-shielded skull, or something similar. Characters that do have moods may not be able to afford such implants, they may have an ethical aversion to altering their minds, or they may simply be too sensitive to moods for these control mechanisms to affect them. It isn't just a matter of money.

  [color=#1e90ff]Having moods is the "intended playstyle" of thaven,[/color] but they are opt-in due to their ability to modify your character out of your control.

  [color=red]Note that a thaven's moods as written are non-diegetic gameplay features.[/color] They should be treated as things that have been integrated into your character's personality, and should not be referenced by their specific names or descriptions. You may choose for your character to be aware that their behavior has changed since their last shift, but they should not be able to recite exactly what is presented to you, the player. [color=#1e90ff]Thaven are, however, fully aware of this phenomenon, and may appropriately refer to them as "moods".[/color]

  [color=#ffa500]These moods should be followed to the best of your ability![/color] A mood being violated yourself or others is uncomfortable or disquieting. The specifics of that are up to you, but if a mood is violated, you should seek to correct the mistake as soon as possible.

  [color=red]Following your moods affords you a limited license to do certain things which would otherwise be against the rules, if approached with proper escalation. If you have a question about this, don't hesitate to ask using the AHelp feature (F1).[/color]

## Mood Swings
  Thaven brains are susceptible to fluctuations in electromagnetic fields. As a result, their ability to synchronize and regulate their moods tends to degrade with extended exposure to the cosmic radiation and ion storms that permeate space stations. [color=#ffa500]It also renders them vulnerable to the EM fields generated by the Syndicate Cryptographic Sequencer, or EMAG,[/color] which can give them additional, often severely debilitating moods if used on an incapacitated thaven. [color=#1e90ff]This feature is disabled by default, but can be enabled in the consent menu.[/color]

  While thaven naturally have moods, they also evolved to live in the protective magnetosphere of a planet. Life in space presents this unique challenge for them. How your character chooses to respond to this fact is up to you.

## Physiology
  The highly specialized nervous system of thaven is capable of discharging electricity from their hands, so [color=#ffa500]their unarmed attacks deal shock damage.[/color]

  Due to sharing a common ancestor with space carp, thaven lungs are strange, resilient organs needed for blood circulation rather than gas exchange, so [color=#ffa500]inhaled gases have no effect on them.[/color] As such, [color=#1e90ff]thaven can safely breathe any kind of atmosphere,[/color] though unlike their genetic lineage, [color=#ffa500]they're still vulnerable to asphyxiation and barotrauma.[/color]

  Note that this also affects thaven undergoing surgery: [color=red]nitrous oxide won't work on them, and surgeons may have to resort to chloral hydrate.[/color]

  All thaven organs contain traces of neurons, and because of this, they take [color=#ffa500]10% more brute and cellular damage, and 20% more radiation damage.[/color] However, their unique ancestry allows them to take [color=#1e90ff]10% less heat, cold, shock, and poison damage.[/color]

  Like space carp, thaven flesh and organs contain carpotoxin. Their blood, while nontoxic, is [color=#ffa500]powerfully hallucinogenic.[/color]

  Thaven mature at the same age as humans, but they live roughly twice as long. Culturally, their lives are generally measured in fifths, with each being about fifty standard years long.

  While thaven tend to be taller than other humanoids on average, they're also naturally flexible, so [color=#1e90ff]they can take the Small trait at a slightly larger size than other species.[/color]

## Language
  Thaven speak Aural, the songlike language of their ancient society.

  Known for its fluid rhythm, melodic tones, and dense vocalizations, it's often described by outsiders as speaking in tongues. Naturally resonant underwater, exposure to Aural has been reported to trigger strange sensory effects in non-thaven listeners - most commonly a soft tingling behind the ears.

  Though hauntingly beautiful, it is notoriously difficult to learn; thaven polyglots often switch languages mid-conversation to spare others from butchering the sound.

  And in every relevant language, the plural of thaven is thaven.

## Thaven Naming Conventions

  Thaven typically name themselves after a single virtue they hold dear. Sometimes these names can be long and unwieldy.

  - [color=#449944]Appropriate:[/color] Honesty
  - [color=#449944]Appropriate:[/color] Have Mercy
  - [color=#449944]Appropriate:[/color] Give Thanks To Thy Ancestors
  - [color=#449944]Appropriate:[/color] Obedience
  - [color=#449944]Appropriate:[/color] Search The Scriptures
  - [color=#994444]Inappropriate:[/color] John Smith
  - [color=#994444]Inappropriate:[/color] Fuck The Police
  - [color=#994444]Inappropriate:[/color] Live Long And Prosper

</Document>
