<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Mnemotechnican
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 VMSolidus
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 sleepyyapril

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT AND AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Glimmer Creatures
As Glimmer rises higher and higher, there can be occasional disturbances in the [color=#a4885c]noosphere[/color].
When new psionic signatures are detected Central Command will make an announcement to the station.
Sometimes these signatures can be the appearance of Glimmer creatures!

Glimmer creatures can appear in numbers as low as 1, or multiple depending on how high Glimmer is and how many psions there are.

These are the entities currently known to NanoTrasen.
Research is ongoing, more are yet to be discovered.

# Glimmer Mite

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobGlimmerMite"/>

The Glimmer mite is a small insect-like being that naturally provokes the noosphere.

Minimum Glimmer rating: Low

## Assessment
As long as it is physically intact it will slowly raise Glimmer.

They show no signs of aggression and are physically harmless.

## Procedure
Kill them as soon as they're spotted, they affect the noosphere and the brooding sound drives crew insane!

## Analysis
You can get liquid [color=#a4885c]Ectoplasm[/color] from blending its body, so they can be a decent source of [color=#a4885c]Normality Crystals[/color].

In an emergency the body can be beaten to a pulp which will make it cease raising Glimmer, at the cost of not yielding ectoplasm.

Overall, a mild help to stopping Glimmer, if you can find them.

# Glimmer Wisp

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobGlimmerWisp"/>

These wisps are physical manifestations of Glimmer that are ghostly in appearance.

Minimum Glimmer rating: High

## Assessment

They don't directly affect the noosphere themselves, the main threat is that they [color=#a4885c]hunt down[/color] any An altar of the gods.s!

Once a psion is critically injured, they will begin to drain the life out of the body to [color=#a4885c]heal all injuries[/color].

## Procedure
Most physical attacks pass through them unnoticed, but holy weapons like the Chaplain's [color=#a4885c]Bible[/color] will weaken it.

Once attacked they will retaliate for some time, so be prepared for a fight!

They can also be dispelled by any gifted psion.

## Analysis
If you manage to kill a wisp, it will leave behind a large amount of ectoplasm which can easily make a drain or two.

Extremely useful to a trained Epistemics team, but will require coordination to take it down.

# Revenant

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobRevenant"/>

A tortured soul taking revenge on those who wronged them, brought to this plane by the noosphere.

Minimum Glimmer rating: Dangerous

## Assessment

They have no effect on the noosphere but are a serious threat to the station, feeding on the souls of dead crew.

Unlike wisps, revenants cannot be attacked in any way by default.

Once a revenant uses their abilities, they can be attacked by any means for a short time.

## Procedure
Holy damage from a bible or anti-psionic knife is especially effective at taking down wisps.

Assistance from the Security department is usually recommended.

Spare no time in putting down a revenant.

## Analysis
Mostly annoying to the crew, limited exploitation due to low amount of ectoplasm when killed.

# Skia

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobSkia"/>

A shadow given form, lashing out at anything that comes too close. Formed by extreme concentrations of glimmer in the noösphere.

Minimum glimmer rating: High

## Assessment

Skia are highly aggressive and will attack anything that comes near them. They typically are drawn to a single individuals psionic resonance, driven to destroy them.

They are vulnerable to anti-psionic weaponary and energy weapons, but highly resistant to physical damage.

The darkness shields them, and they are capable of rapidly regenerating from any injuries provided the area is shrouded in darkness.

Their very presence disrupts the noösphere, and can lead to a chain reaction of further glimmer creature manifestations.

## Procedure
Spectral locaters can be used to track their movements. When in darkness they are nearly totally invisible. Bright lights can be used to reveal them, and weaken their regenerative capabilities.

Assistance from the security department is usually recommended.

Spare no time in putting down a Skia. Once it has located its target, it will relentlessly pursue them until they are dead.

## Analysis
Extremely dangerous to the crew, but a large source of ectoplasm when killed. If they are not put down swiftly they can cause mass casualties.
</Document>
