<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Alice
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Shaman
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 sleepyyapril

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
## Mantis

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SomberHangingBrazier" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WallDecorSomberPsi" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SomberHangingBrazier" Caption=""/>
</Box>

[color=#a65ccc]Mantes are psionic specialists[/color] formally trained by either the secretive Outer Chamber or, less commonly, through an apprenticeship with an elder mantis. They are assigned by Nanotrasen to serve within Epistemics, [color=#a65ccc]and their ultimate purpose is to protect the natural order of reality.[/color] A mantis works to confront supernatural threats that bleed into the material world from the noosphere; to intervene when psionic powers are misused in ways that endanger the crew or compromise existential stability; and to help station's psions understand, endure, and safely wield their abilities.

Their duties begin where ordinary expertise ends: where noospheric storms twist perception, where psionic forces exceed containment, and where subtle distortions foretell breaches in the fabric of the world. [color=#ffd069]Their role is advisory, custodial, and metaphysical--not judicial.[/color]

Though mantes work within Epistemics, [color=#ffd069]they should generally only assist with routine research duties when necessary or when tasked by their immediate supervisor, the Mystagogue.[/color] Their priority is always the metaphysical health of the station, not anomalies or artifacts. Idly helping your coworkers is acceptable, but do not allow it to eclipse your true responsibilities.

The Outer Chamber recognizes specializations among experienced mantes:

- [color=#a65ccc]Mantis Exorcists hunt otherworldly entities[/color] that threaten the safety of the station and its crew.
- [color=#a65ccc]Mantis Occultists monitor for psionic misconduct[/color] and investigate signs of noospheric tampering, corruption, or instability.
- [color=#a65ccc]Mantis Spiritualists guide psions through awakening,[/color] helping them integrate their abilities without losing themselves.

These titles are callings, rather than ranks. A mantis may embody more than one, but should know which voice speaks first.

## Equipment and Usage

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ForensicMantisPDA" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LanternMantis" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="VendingMachineSomberMantis" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingBackpackCoffinMantis" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HandheldPsionicsRegistry" Caption=""/>
</Box>

The occult tools found in mantis offices are tailored to their unique tasks, including psychoactive chemicals, ritual papers, and sensing amulets. [color=#a65ccc]Their pill canisters are also color-coded for clarity and safety.[/color] Some mantes may choose to bring additional equipment to the station, such as restraints for use during volatile psionic assessments, [color=#d9418d]but these should never be used for criminal arrests.[/color]

[color=#ffd069]If a psion is suspected of wrongdoing, you must notify Security and defer to their lawful procedures unless your life or another's is in immediate danger. Do not place yourself at risk simply to justify the use of force.[/color]

[color=#a65ccc]You may use your handheld psion registry as you see fit,[/color] whether to track the development of awakening psions or to note behavior that may merit Security review. Be aware that all entries are transmitted to the Epistemics radio channel.

Mantes are issued special weapons to confront forces that ordinary armaments may struggle against. Additionally, [color=#a65ccc]all mantis outerwear is lightly armored[/color] to help them withstand metaphysical confrontation without appearing militarized.

[color=#d9418d]Your equipment is not an invitation to escalate. It is insurance against the unknowable.[/color]

## Mnemolith Weapons

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MantisMeleeKnife" Caption="Athame"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MantisMeleeSickle" Caption="Boline"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MantisMeleeCane" Caption="Gnomon"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MantisMeleeFist" Caption="Manifold"/>
</Box>

Mantis melee implements are carved from [color=#a65ccc]mnemolith[/color], a dark, glassy stone formed in the wake of extreme noospheric storms. It resonates with psionic essence, and in the hands of one who intends harm, it behaves accordingly, cutting where ordinary matter would fail. [color=#a65ccc]All mnemolith weapons inflict +25% damage against psions and cause metaphysical harm in addition to their physical strikes.[/color]

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MantisMeleeGreatsword" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MantisMeleeGreatswordSheathFilled" Caption=""/>
</Box>

Certain mnemolith artifacts are volatile, [color=#ffd069]and may severely injure a wielder who strikes non-psionic targets with them--including pests, furniture, or even walls.[/color] Treat unusual resonance as a warning, not a challenge; if a weapon hums, flickers, or strains against your grip, [color=#ffd069]reconsider why you are holding it.[/color]

[color=#d9418d]Misusing mnemolith against crew without cause is a criminal act.[/color]

## Firearms and Casters

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MantisRangedPistol" Caption="Kalliste"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MantisRangedRevolver" Caption="Charon"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MantisRangedSubMachineGun" Caption="Strix"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MantisRangedShotgun" Caption="Empusa"/>
</Box>

Mantis firearms are unique models that utilize specialized [color=#a65ccc]casters[/color] instead of traditional magazines. These devices harness exotic anomaly cores to generate physical ammunition internally, and each caster alters the firearm's purpose. [color=#a65ccc]Most recharge over time,[/color] and all can be accelerated using a standard cell recharger. [color=#ffd069]All firearms have access to all types of casters.[/color]

[color=#d9418d]Firearms are tools of last resort, not instruments of authority.[/color]

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MantisCasterPistolHoly" Caption="Pistol (Banishing)"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MantisCasterRevolverCrypto" Caption="Revolver (Silencing)"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MantisCasterSubMachineGunCapgun" Caption="SMG (Training)"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MantisCasterShotgunLethal" Caption="Shotgun (Piercing)"/>
</Box>

- [color=#a65ccc]Banishing[/color] casters cause metaphysical damage only. Effective against otherworldly phenomena, harmless against crew.
- [color=#a65ccc]Silencing[/color] casters inject cryptobiolin. A full caster's dose suppresses a psion's abilities for twenty minutes.
- [color=#ffd069]Training[/color] casters fire caps that produce only light, sound, and recoil. Useful for practice, if found.
- [color=#d9418d]Piercing[/color] casters fire sharpened diamond projectiles, [color=#d9418d] and are not authorized aboard Nanotrasen facilities.[/color]

## Expectations

[color=#a65ccc]Your words solve more problems than any blade ever will.[/color] As a mantis, conversation, mediation, and discernment are your principal instruments. While you are capable of violence, [color=#ffd069]you are not appointed to dispense it against crew.[/color]

[color=#d9418d]Mindbreaking is not your right, privilege, or duty.[/color] The pills provided to you can permanently sever a mind's connection to the noosphere without extraordinary intervention, a fate one may compare to clipping a wild bird's wings. [color=#ffd069]Such an act is only to be performed when explicitly requested by the Captain or a greater authority[/color]--or possibly by the psion themselves. As the one performing the act, [color=#a65ccc]you have the right to refuse if you deem it too cruel a punishment.[/color] Chemists are capable of producing mindbreaker toxin, and you may legally remove yourself from the situation.

[color=#a65ccc]When in doubt, contact Central Command for confirmation before administering the dose.[/color]

## Final Notes

- Never forget that psions are not your enemy. [color=#a65ccc]You are a psion too, after all.[/color]
- Except in true catastrophes, [color=#ffd069]you will spend more time counseling and monitoring psions than hunting supernatural threats.[/color]
- You are not Security. [color=#d9418d]Report suspected psionic misconduct rather than intervening alone.[/color]
- There is no Inner Chamber. Do not speculate about it, and do not indulge those who do.

</Document>
